Guide to the Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Cecile Starr Papers,
1925-2001.
Starr, Cecile.
5 linear ft. (ca. 5,000 items in 10 boxes)
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4079913
Personal documents, photographs, audio cassettes, and printed material of the filmmaker, frlm writer, and educator Cecile Starr.
Biographical Note
Filmmaker, frlm writer, and educator Cecile Starr was born in Nashville, TN (July 14, 1921) and grew up in New Orleans, LA. She received a B.A. in Romance Languages (LSU, 1941) and a masters degree in Adult Education (Columbia University. Teachers College, 1952); after which she taught film history and criticism in Columbia's Graduate Film department (1955-1961). Starr worked as non-thratrical writer and editor for the quarterly Film Forum Review (1946-1949) and the weekly Saturday Review (1949-1959). She also published free-lance articles in The New York Times and various film journals (sometimes on highly controversal subjects). Starr wrote or edited four books: Ideas on Film (1951); Film Society Primer (1956); Discovering the Movies (1972); Experimental Animation, with Robert Russett (1976, revised 1988). As a scriptwriter and producer, her films include the award-winning Fellow Citizen, A. Lincoln and Islamic Carpets.
For 35 years Staff has worked as a part-time, home-based distributor, renting and selling films on behalf of friends and colleagues, including Alexander Alexeieff and Claire Parker, Helen Levitt, Mary Ellen Bute, Hans Richter and others. In 1977 she founded and became co-director of the Women's Independent Film Exchange, and in 1991 she received one of the Anthology Film Archive's Fiulm Preservation award. Starr married filmmaker Aram Boyajian in 1957. They have two children and one grandson.
Scope and Content
Personal documents, photographs, audio cassettes (primarily interviews of Starr and others), and printed material. Family and personal correspondence; professional correspondence; materials relating to Southern writers including James Agee, Peter Fritsch, and Randall Jarrell; materials related to her secondary, college, and university education; teaching materials regarding filmmaking courses taught at Columbia University, the New School, and elsewhere; and manuscripts and preparation materials for published and unpublished articles.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in nine series.
Seris I: Starr family
Series II: Cecile Starr
Series III: Aram Boyajian
Series IV: New York Film Activities, 1940s & 1950s
SeriesV: Teaching at Columbia University, 1955-1961
Series VI: Film Criticism
Series: VII: Articles with Related Correspondence
Series VIII: Film Activities, 1980s-1990s
Series IX: Cassette Recordings
Subjects
Columbia University.; New School University.; Agee, James, 1909-1955.; Boyajian, Aram.; Jarrell, Randall, 1914-1965.; Motion picture industry.; Motion pictures--History and criticism.; Agreements.; Announcements.; Articles.; Audio cassettes.; Autobiographies.; Certificates.; Contracts.; Diplomas.; Financial records.; Fliers (printed matter).; Invitations.; Licenses.; Lists.; Manuscripts.; Memorials.; Notes.; Obituaries.; Programs.; Photographs.; Receipts.; Resumes.; Reviews.; Rosters.; Wills.; Teachers.; Authors, American.; Independent filmmakers.; Motion picture producers and directors.; Women authors, American.; Women motion picture producers and directors.; Women teachers.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
1998 M-1998 Papers Starr, Cecile Gift
Gift of Cecile Starr, 1998.
- Series I: Starr Family
  - Alfred and Elizabeth Starr. Correspondence (Elizabeth) and clippings. [v.p.] [n.d.] 1952-1997 6 pages t.l.s. 3 p.c.s. 14 pages photocopies 6 pages (Box 1, Folder 1)
    (Newspaper and periodical clippings related to the career and death of Alfred Starr. Includes controversial public debate over subject of "pay T.V.")
  - Starr, Carrie and Cecile Starr. Letter to Starr and Lightman families. New York 29 March 1997 3 pages t.l.s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    (Descriptive letter regarding funeral of Carrie Lightman Starr (mother) and Starr burial site in Nashville, TN.)
  - Starr, Jacob. Copies of marriage and obituary clippings; copy of will. Nashville, TN [n.d.], 30 April 1932 1 page photocopy 2 page t.ms Note: Father of Cecile Starr., (Poor quality copy of newspaper clippings.) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Starr, Milton and Goldie "Zaro" Starr (Mrs. Milton). To: Cecile Starr [v.p.] [n.d.] 1934-1996 21 pages a.l.s. 1 page t.l.s. 1 p.c.s (Box 1, Folder 4)
    (Paternal uncle and aunt of Cecile Starr.)
  - Starr, Milton. Obituary and memorial tributes by William R. MacKaye and Michael Wolf[v.p.] 1976 1 page photocopy 5 pages t.ms. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Freud, Sigmund. Biography by Ernest Jones The Life and Work of Sigmund Freud, Vol III. Page 233. [n.p.] [n.d.] 1 page photocopy (Box 1, Folder 6)
    (References to Milton Starr's financial support of psychoanalysis periodical "Imago.")
  - Lowell, Robert. Robert Lowell: A Biography by Ian Hamilton. Pages 47, 66. [n.p.] [n.d.] 2 pages photocopies (Box 1, Folder 7)
    (References to Milton Starr's financial support of the American poet.)
  - Waters, Ethel. Excerpts from Waters autobiography His Eye is on the Sparrow. Pages 156, 160, 170-171. [n.p.] 1950 2 pages t.ms. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    (Excerpts typed onto separate sheets. Description of Milton Starr's support of African American artists)
  - Bijou Amusement Company Partnership. To Cecile Starr. Stock certificates. [n.p.] 29 December 1960 3 pages t.l.s (Box 1, Folder 9)
    (See also "The Reluctant Capitalist"; file 74.)
  - Starr, Mike. To Cecile Starr [n.p.] [n.d.] 3 pages a.l.s. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Starr, Sarah Lusky. Clippings of obituaries. [n.p.] 4 December 1925 1 page photocopy (Box 1, Folder 11)
    (Paternal grandmother of Cecile Starr.)
  - Starr, Bessie (Mrs. David). To Cecile Starr [n.p.] 23 Oct 1985 28 Jan 1986 1 p.c.s. 1 page t.l.s (Box 1, Folder 12)
    (Paternal aunt of Cecile Starr. Includes letter from Jeanne Starr Loeb regarding death of Bessie Starr.)
  - To Cecile Starr Tennessee 25 January 1980 1 p.c.s (Box 1, Folder 13.)
    (From "Mary Jane" [Coleman] inquiring about relation to Afred Starr)
  - Starr, Joseph (J.D.). To Cecile Starr. Includes correspondence between Cecile to J.D. Starr [v.p.] [n.d.] 1934-1998 1 p.c.s. 94 pages a. and t.l.s. 15 pages a. and t.l.s (Box 1, Folder 14)
    (Brother to Cecile Starr.)
  - Starr Joseph (J.D). Miscellaneous personal items: birth certificate, confirmation program, business card, newspaper clippings; New Yorker article regarding "Pennies from Heaven"; funeral condolences. [v.p.] [n.d.] 1929-1999 3 items 5 pages photocopies 1 page periodical 3 a.l.s. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Loeb, Jeanne Starr. Letters and newspaper clippings; paraphernalia [v.p.] [n.d.] 1985-2000 1 Folder 2 pages (Box 1, Folder 16)
    (Cousin to Cecile Starr.)
  - Letters and paraphenalia regarding activity of children and grandchildren of Milton and Zaro Starr. [v.p.] [n.d.] 1972-2000 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 17.)
  - Letters and paraphenalia regarding children and grandchildren of Alfred Starr. [v.p.] [n.d.] 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 18.)
  - Starr Carrie (Lightman). Memoir written by Carrie Starr with notes by Cecile Starr [n.p.] [n.d.] 55 t.ms. 26 a.ms. 1 Folder 2 note pages a.ms.s. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    (Mother of Cecile Starr)
  - Starr Carrie (Lightman). To Cecile Starr; letters from Cecile to Carrie Starr; funeral mementos. [n.p.] [n.d.] 1944-1984 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
    (Mother of Carrie Starr.)
  - Correspondence to Cecile and Carrie from members of the Lightman family. [v.p.] 1937-1997 2 Folder inserts (Box 1, Folder 21)
    (Includes clippings and publicity items.)
  - Lightman, Alan. Photocopies of correspondence with Cecile Starr [v.p.] 1984-1998 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Lightman, Alan. Photocopies of book reviews by and of Alan Lightman; paraphernalia [v.p.] 1982-2001 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Series II: Cecile Starr
  - Starr Cecile. Personal documents: copy of birth certificate, wedding invitation, wedding license, resume, personal will, financial and legal documents; typed memoir with corrections. [v.p.] New York [n.d.] 1957-1995 1 Folder 5 pages t.ms. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Starr Cecile. School records; detailed childhood and contemporary recollections handwritten by Starr; McMain High School annual (1937); mementos. New Orleans, LA 1921-1942 1 Folder (Box 2, Folder 25)
    (Filed by Cecile Starr "New Orleans 1921-1937.")
  - Joseph, Eleanor Cohen. Correspondence with Cecile Starr. [n.p.] 1944-1996 1 Folder (Box 2, Folder 26)
    (Distant Lightman cousin of Cecile Starr.)
  - Louisiana State University. Personal and administrative correspondence; diploma Baton Rouge, LA 1937-1941 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    (Correspondence with friends extends beyond college years.)
  - Fritsch, Peter. Correspondence with Peter Fritsch; articles and clippings regarding Fritsch, Mia Fritsch and James Agee. [v.p.] [n.d.] 1940-1990 1 Folder (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence and clippings regarding Southern writers including James Agee, Randall Jarrell, Robert Lowell. [v.p.] [n.d.] 1953-1989 1 Folder (Box 2, Folder 29)
    (Filed by Cecile Starr "Growing Up in the Literary South.")
  - Stafford, Jean. Varies items include articles, photocopies of two way correspondence; correspondence with rare book collectors, clippings, excerpts of Stafford's writing, personal accounts by Starr. [v.p.] 1978-1998 1 Folder (Box 11, Folder 103)
    (Original copies of correspondence and materials purchased by the University of Colorado at Boulder.)
- Series III: Aram Boyajian
  - Boyajian, Aram. Correspondence and materials regarding early film projects; personal notes. [v.p.] 1922-1970 1 Folder (Box 3, Folder 30)
    (Previously organized by Cecile Starr:"Aram Boyajian to 1970." Includes personal account of Emmy Award Ceremony 1964 won by Boyajian for editting "The Kremlin.")
  - Boyajian, Aram. Professional correspondence, clippings, personal accounts. Published volume of poetry: The Man Who Wrote the World's Longest Haiku, Crossing Press, NY. 1973. [v.p.] [n.d.] 1970-1996 1 Folder 1 volume bd (Box 3, Folder 31)
    (Previously organized by Cecile Starr "Aram Boyajian from 1970 on.")
  - Boyajian, Aram. ABC-TV. Published volume based on ABC-TV documentary "Africa" produced by Boyajian and others. [n.p.] [n.d.] 1 vol., bd. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Boyajian, Aram. ABC-TV. Materials regarding documentary "Kitty Genovese." New York 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    (Includes personal correspondence between Boyajian and convicted murderer Winston Moseley; photocopy of childhood memoir.)
  - ABC-TV. Clippings of reviews and materials regarding documentary "The American Indian" written and produced by Boyajian. [n.p.] 1972 1 Folder (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - HBO and Consumer Reports.. Correspondence regarding documentaries "Earth to Kids" and "Unsafe at Any Race." New York 1984, 1991 1 Folder (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Boyajian family correspondence. [v.p.] [n.d.] 1971-1993 1 Folder (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Boyajian, Suzanne. Correspondence and miscellaneous items. [v.p.] 1980-1996 1 Folder (Box 3, Folder 37)
    (Daughter of Cecile Starr and Aram Boyajian)
  - Boyajian, Marco. High school diploma, resume; correspondence; clippings regarding store Showtime Video in Burlington, Vermont. [v.p.] New York, Vermont 1978-1997 1 Folder (Box 3, Folder 38)
    (Son of Cecile Starr and Aram Boyajian.)
  - Boyajian, Marco. Film reviews by Marco Boyajian. [v.p.] 1969-1998 1 Folder Note: Son of Cecile Starr and Aram Boyajian. (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Series IV: New York Film. 1940s and 1950s
  - Jack Ellis. Film Council of America. Correspondence to and from Starr; incomplete manuscript of autiographical materials [author unclear]. Evanston, IL and Vermont 1981-1997 1 Folder (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Clippings, flyers, personal correspondence regarding filmmakers Julien Bryan, Ken Snelson, Francis Thompson. New York 1970s-1980s 1 Folder Note: All filmmakers who began careers in New York during the 1940s and 1950s. (Box 4, Folder 41)
    (Previously arranged by Cecile Starr.)
  - Clippings regarding film careers of Jim Davis and James Broughton. New York 1940s-1950s 1 Folder Note: Includes published volume "Jim Davis: The Flow of Energy" inscribed to Cecile Starr. (Box 4, Folder 42)
    (Previously filed as "Rosalind Kossoff" by Starr.)
  - Thomas Brandon and Leo Dratfield. Correspondence and personal notes. New York 1967-1982 1 Folder Note: Note by Starr regarding relationship between filmmaker and distributor. (Box 4, Folder 43)
    (Previously filed by Starr.)
  - Lillian Wachtel. Film News. Clippings and correspondence regarding periodical "Film News" and film publisher and editor Rohana Lee. Vermont and New York [n.d.]; 1965, 1997 1 Folder (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Wachtel, Lillian. Clippings and correspondence with Cecile Starr. [n.p.] 1999-2001 1 Folder (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Austrailian News and Information Bureau. Correspondence, clippings, and personal notes. New York 1942-1977 1 Folder Note: Cecile Starr's employer from 1942-1945. Includes correspondence between Cecile Starr and Australian filmmaker Ronald Maslyn Williams to 1977 with references to Jean Stafford, wife of poet Robert Lowell. References regarding office environment and newswriters during World War II. (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Affiliated Film Producers. Personal correspondence and accounts, clippings regarding Starr's working acquaintance with Willard Van Dyke, Irving Jacoby, and Helen Grayson; obituary for Irving Jacoby written by Starr published in EFLA Newsletter. New York 1967-1997 1 Folder (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Film Council of America. "A Symposium: Sixty Years of 16 mm Film" and "A Guide to Film Services of National Associations." Practical Offset Inc.: Des Plaines IL 1954 220 pages bd. 146 pages bd (Box 4, Folder 48)
    (Cecile Starr on the editorial board.)
  - Film Council of America. Correspondence, programs, t.ms. of essay by Starr published in memorial flyer (1996). New York 1959-1996 1 Folder (Box 4, Folder 49)
    (Personal accounts regarding activities in the 1940s and 1950s Cecile Starr on the editorial board)
  - National Film Board of Canada. Flyers, correspondence, personal accounts. New York and Montreal 1956-1979 1 Folder (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Sophie Hohne (Reu). March of Time. Correspondence, flyers, clippings, photographs of building where former office stood. New York 1970-1997 1 Folder (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Miscellaneous events and projects 1940s-1950s. Correspondence, clippings; study guides and articles for Encyclopedia Britannica by Cecile Starr. New York 1940-1950 1 Folder (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Series V: Teaching at Columbia University 1955-1961
  - Correspondence and clippings regarding former students:Alfred Appel, Jr.; Timothy Asch; John Frazer; Gordon Hendricks; George Manupelli; Roger Sandall; Don Gunn. New York 1955-1961 1 Folder (Box 5, Folder 53)
    (Correspondence extends into later years.)
  - Correspondence to and from former students: James Watters, Howard Worth, Merle Worth, Herbert Reynolds [not a student, an acquaintence]. New York 1955-1961 1 Folder (Box 5, Folder 54)
    (Filed by Starr: "First class of M.A. Film and TV students at Columbia.)
  - Bogdonavich and De Palma. Correspondence, personal accounts, and materials regarding former students Peter Bogdonavich and Brian de Palma New York 1955-1975 1 Folder (Box 5, Folder 55)
    (Correspondence with Bogdonavich 1972-1975)
  - Educational records and correspondence New York 1947-2001 1 Folder (Box 5, Folder 56)
    (Includes written statement regarding disagreement with Erik Barnouw and leave of absence to go to Paris with husband. Filed by Cecile Starr "Columbia University-miscellaneous.")
  - Teaching materials including typed notes include student notes from Starr's history of the motion picture course (1960), correspondence, film periodical clippings, programs, and flyers. New York 1955-1961 1 Folder (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Life. Published articles by Jim Watters. Time, Inc.: Chicago February 1980 May, 1986 2 vol. bd (Box 5, Folder 58)
    (Former student of Cecile Starr.)
- Series VI: Film Criticism
  - Kael, Pauline. Articles; clippings; one incomplete typed ms. regarding film critic. [v.p.] 1968-1989 1 Folder (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Gerstein, Evelyn. Notes, correspondence between film critic Gerstein and Starr, handwrittten manuscript, clippings, photocopies of Gerstein's film reviews. [v.p.] New York [n.d.] 1961-1986 1 Folder (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Agee, James. Personal account by Starr on her acquaintance with Agee; periodical and book excerpts, handwritten notes. [v.p.] New York [n.d.] 1959-1984 1 Folder (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence, notes, clippings regarding critics including Archer Winstein and Virgil Thomson. [v.p.] 1960-1997 1 Folder (Box 6, Folder 62)
    (Filed by Starr "American Film Critics and Writers.")
  - Notes and papers for class on Film Criticism taught by Starr. New York [1960s-1970s] 1 Folder (Box 6, Folder 63)
    (Drawn from courses taught at the New School, Columbia University, and elsewhere.)
  - Movie reviews by students of Cecile Starr at the New School. New York 1974-1980 1 Folder (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Thompson, Howard. Personal accounts by Cecile Starr; clippings of articles by film columnist and longtime acquaintance. Book inscribed to Starr by Howard: The Female Approach by Ronald Searle. Knopf, NY. 1954. [v.p.] New York 1944-1997 1 Folder (Box 6, Folder 65)
    (Film writer for the New York Times.)
  - Notes, clippings. New York 1956-1987 1 Folder (Box 6, Folder 66)
    (Information on film critics at the New York Times including Mordaunt Hall, Vincent Canby, Frank Nugent, and Bosley Crowther.)
- Series VII: Articles (with related correspondence)
  - Levitt, Helen. Notes, materials, drafts, and clipping of articles written by Cecil Starr. Appeared in two publications: "Center Quarterly," Summer 1985. Vol. 6, No. 4. Book Review, "Sightlines," Winter 1986/87. 2 published volumes: "Helen Levitt" and "Helen Levitt: Photographies." [v.p.] France, New York 1977-1988 3 Folders (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Deren, Maya. The New York Times. Correspondence and notes regarding Cecile Starr article: "The Mother of the American Avant-Garde Film," 2 May 1976. New York 1976 1 Folder (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - The New York Times. Typed ms. (draft), notes, correspondence, photocopy and clipping of article by Cecile Starr: "Is the Government Subsidizing Sexism in Film" in The New York Times?" 9 January 1977. New York 1977 1 Folder (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - House Beautiful. Notes, correspondence and sample copy of column by Cecile Starr: "Flowers and Films for Spring" January 1953. Vol. 95, No. 1 Hearst Corp.: New York 1953-1954 1 Folder (Box 7, Folder 70)
    (Starr wrote a film column from 1953-1954. Correspondence with editor Joseph Barry dates into the 1980s.)
  - American Film Institute.. Clippings and articles. Printed letter from Cecile Starr: "Film Artists Fear AFI Will Go Hollywood," in Readers and Writers, April-May 1967. Subsequent correspondence. [v.p.] New York 1967-1981 1 Folder (Box 7, Folder 71)
    (Starr's critical letter regarding the vision of the Film Advisory Council of the National Council of the Arts--Hollywood/entertainment vs. art received a wide public response. Correspondence includes photocopy of a letter from Council member and actor Gregory Peck (29 May 1967).)
  - Anthology Film Archive Jonas Mekas Film Culture. Flyers, announcements, letters, and correspondence regarding article by Cecile Starr: "New York Letter" in Sight and Sound, Winter 1961/62. New York 1961-1998 1 Folder (Box 7, Folder 72)
    (Personal account of Cecile Starr's Preservation Award and ceremony given her by Anthology Film Archives in 1992.)
  - The Saturday Review. Notes, correspondence, clippings, photograph of former office site. New York 1949-1959 1 Folder (Box 7, Folder 73)
    (Cecile Starr worked for The Saturday Review 1949-1959. Includes what she considered her ten best columns. Correspondence extends through 1997.)
  - The New York Times. Notes and correspondence regarding Starr article: "The Reluctant Capitalist" printed 15 October 1995. [v.p.] New York 1950-1995 1 Folder (Box 7, Folder 74)
    (Non-film related.)
  - Mazursky, Paul. Correspondence from and to Starr. Notes and materials for Starr's two publications regarding Mazursky's "An Unmarried Woman." Twentieth Century Fox, "Talking Cinematically re. Films," 1978. "Women in Film: Weill and Mazursky," Fire Island News, August 19, 1978. New York 1978 1 Folder (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Richter, Hans. Personal correspondence with Richter; correspondence regarding Richter's estate; announcements and flyers relevant to the filmmaker's career. [v.p.] 1974-1998 1 Folder (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - Brakhage, Stan. Correspondence and clippings regarding filmmaker Brakhage. New York 1979-1998 1 Folder (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Posner, Bruce. Correspondence; clippings regarding Posner's filmaking career. [v.p.] 1983-1998 1 Folder (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - Richter, Hans. Correspondence (includes letter from Jonas Mekas), notes, transcripts of tapes, drafts, writings by Richter, and photocopies of Starr writings regarding Richter. "Richter on Film: An Independent Film about an Independent Filmmaker," Art & Cinema, December 1978. "Notes on Hans Richter in the U.S.A.," No. 79, Winter 1996. "Hilla Rebay and the Guggenheim Nexus," [no source information.] [v.p.] New York 1977-1996 1 Folder (Box 11, Folder 102)
- Series VIII: Film Activities 1980s-1990s
  - Kertesz Project Paris 1986-1987 1 Folder (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Museum of Modern Art. Clippings, notes, and inventory lists; correspondence. New York 1980-1997 1 Folder (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Southern filmmakers; correspondence, critiques, rosters of film festivals. [v.p.] 1975-1982 1 Folder (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Correspondence, loose pages from published script, typed draft for article on movie: "Tattoo." [v.p.] 1959-1983 1 Folder Note: Article never published. Filed by Starr: "Tattoo article-Bob Brooks." (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Centre Georges Pompidou. Correspondence, contract, and draft of Starr article on Stephanie Maxwell Paris and Vermont 1993-1997 1 Folder (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - American Federation of the Arts. Copy of distribution agreement, correspondence, flyer for film festival in Baton Rouge. Baton Rouge [n.d] 1977-1989 1 Folder (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Boyajian Starr Associates. Notes, Employer Identification Number, financial records. New York 1979-1985 1 Folder (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Correspondence and related items for various film periodicals. [n.p.] 1961-1985 1 Folder Note: Includes "Spiral," "Film Quarterly," and "Cantrills." (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Receipts from personal sale of used film related books, videos, and posters. [v.p.] New York 1989-1994 1 Folder (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Curtis, David. Arts Council of Great Britain. To Cecile Starr England 1981-1984 1 Folder (Box 8, Folder 85)
    (Regarding film program notes and project proposals.)
  - Miscellaneous film correspondence 1990s New York [n.d.] 1995, 1998 1 Folder Note: Includes Maxine Haleff, Vachel Blair, Sally Mason-Robinson, Paula Kotis. (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Clippings and correspondence regarding film education and teaching positions. [v.p.] 1980-1999 1 Folder (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Lye, Len. Clippings, correspondence, and materials regarding career of the kinetic sculptor and experimental filmmaker Len Lye (1901-1980). [v.p.] 1936-1991 1 Folder (Box 8, Folder 88)
    (Photocopy of letter to Starr signed "Len.")
  - Lincoln Center programs and exhibition notes; t.ms. of talk given by Starr during 1967-1968 school year. New York 1967-1989 1 Folder (Box 9, Folder 89)